Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Hello!
Here I am.
Here, look!
Come.
Come, you can sit in my shade.
There it is. You see this place?
This is my village.
My village is filled with goodness.
The villagers too...
are very good people.
Every tree probably thinks
that about its own village.
My respected Ramachandrayya always says,
When you look at things with a good heart,
everything will look good, son.
His heart is kind.
His words are even kinder.
You wouldn't know Ramachandrayya,
would you?
You're standing in my shadow, right?
That shade is his.
I see the world through his eyes.
I grew up with him.
My Ramachandrayya shares
everything with me.
He is my world.
He is my life.
He planted me when
Mahatma Gandhi passed away.
I was once just a tiny sapling...
and now, I'm so big!
My Ramchandrayya adores Mahatma Gandhi.
He's always reading about
Gandhi's life story.
Always talking about his life.
My Ramchandrayya has a granddaughter too.
Can you guess her name?
Look how she giggles with joy.
Shall we name her 'Gandhi'?
Oh father, Gandhi is not a girl's name.
It's a name the whole world admires.
Why can't it be a girl's name?
Let's name her Gandhi.
Gandhi!
You like the name, don't you?
Ah! Look, she likes it!
The baby girl likes Gandhi!
Your name is Gandhi, okay?
This story belongs to us.
Gandhi, Grandfather and Tree.
Gandhi?
Gandhi.
Dear.
What is it, Grandpa?
Wake up, child.
You have to go to school. Get up, dear.
Get up.
Did you study well for the exam?
Yes, I did.
Where are you off to so early?
I am going to the temple, dear.
I'm going to pray that you do well
in the exam.
Here's some money for your laddus.
My grandfather never fails to
remember this.
Can I leave now?
Yes, all right.
Grandpa...
Yes, dear.
Be careful when climbing and
descending the stairs. Okay?
Okay, dear.
Shall I leave now?
- All the best. Okay?
- Okay.
I'll see you soon.
My little princess.
Father, father
What?
I'm leaving for school.
I have my exam today.
So? Why wake me up?
You want me to write the exam?
Let it be. You sleep.
Father, father...
Girl, what is your problem?
You are going to the town, aren't you?
Can you get a new pair of slippers
for Mom, please?
The old ones are torn. Poor thing,
she walks bare feet everywhere.
Okay, you can go.
Daddy...
What is it now?
Won't you wish me 'All the best'?
If I wish you 'All the best,'
will you get good marks?
If you write well, you'll pass.
Else, you'll fail.
Also, you are a girl.
Whether you pass or fail,
it doesn't matter.
Don't wake me up again or I'll slap you.
Okay... sleep.
Hey child! Don't run!
You'll spoil my Rangoli design.
What is that hair?
You look like a mad woman.
Wait, let me braid it.
I braided my hair myself.
Does it not look good?
It's terrible.
You look like a begger woman.
If anyone sees, they'll think
you're a beggar.
Why should we care what others think, Ma?
Bah!
Don't argue with me
so early in the morning.
Do whatever you want. Go.
Ma, did you forget I have an exam today?
Oh no, I forgot!
Take this with you.
Give this money to the shopkeeper.
- Did you pack your lunchbox?
- Yes, I did!
Eat it yourself.
Don't share your lunch with anyone.
I've made your favorite potato curry.
- Okay?
- Okay.
I'll eat some and share some
with Mallesh and Chenulu.
They just love your potato curry.
Again you talk of sharing. Don't their
mothers know how to cook potato curry?
Why do they always eat your lunch?
Okay Ma, I'm getting late.
I'll leave now.
Go carefully!
How will she even survive in this world!
Brother, Ma asked me to give you
this money.
Ah, you're my first customer today,
Gandhi.
Brother, give me two sesame laddus.
Forget laddus, there's a new chocolate,
in the market.
I can't even pronounce its name...
- What chocolate, Brother?
- It's called, wait...
Alpinn... Something... I've kept it in
this box.
All the kids are asking for it.
Brother…
None of these can match
sister's sesame laddus.
Give me two sesame laddus, Brother.
Seems like your sister makes these
laddus only for you.
No one else buys them.
Here's your change.
Brother, you gave me two rupees extra.
Oh...
My dear child!
How sweet of you to return the money.
I returned what is yours, Brother.
That's all.
I'm getting late for my exam.
Please give my regards to Sister.
Go
Go.
Psst…
Psst… Mallesh…
What is it?
Sir, Mallesh and Chenulu are copying.
Sir, don't hit us. It'll hurt, sir.
Are you some kind of flower,
that I'll treat you delicately?
Show me your palm. Show me your palm!
Sir... We were copying because
you hit us if we fail.
Else, why would we copy, sir?
Don't act smart with me.
I asked you to study well
and pass the exam.
Not to copy and pass the exam!
Mallesh!
Do you have any shame?
You're the village head's grandson.
Aren't you ashamed, copying in the exams?
Come, let's go meet your grandfather.
Come on, let's go!
Sir, let's settle this between us.
Why bring my grandfather into this.
Show me your palm. Show me!
Sir!
Don't hit them, sir!
They will have pain.
Gandhi. You can't decide everything.
If you didn't want them punished,
why did you report them to me?
I wouldn't have noticed them.
You write your exam.
Sir, you can hit her instead of us.
You've gotten too smart these days.
- Sir...
- Sir... Sir...
- Sir... Sir... Sir...
Look, Mr. Ramachandra...
What's the use of all the education?
You are educated and your father too...
But what are you doing?
You both are working in your fields, aren't you?
You educated your son too,
he too is unemployed.
Then, what's the use of education?
No matter how educated one is,
everyone feels the hunger, right?
If everyone quits agriculture,
how will the world get food?
Education gives you knowledge
and farming gives you food.
There is nothing wrong if a farmer gets educated,
similarly, there is nothing wrong in an
educated man choosing to do farming.
Shall I tell you one thing, Mr. Ramchandra?
Your son called my son who works in the city,
he was asking to look for a job for him.
He is educated, why don't you
send him to the city?
Look, Patela...
If he had ambition which requires him to
migrate to a city, I wouldn't have stopped him.
But he wants to go there to earn a livelihood.
There's a nice difference between
being successful and earning a livelihood.
For his education, he would, at most,
get a job as a watchman or a driver.
But he wouldn't understand this.
- Greetings, Sir.
- Greetings to you too, sir.
What happened?
What brings you all here?
Sir...
The factory refuses to
accept our sugarcane.
They are not paying us well either.
What? How can they do this?
No idea, sir.
We don't know why they are doing so.
Didn't you ask them?
We did. They said
the quality isn't good enough.
The factory is apparently in losses, sir.
I heard they might shut it down.
My brother-in-law works at the factory.
He told me the other day. I told them
but they don't believe me.
What are you saying, Sampath?
How can they close the factory?
We took loans to grow our sugarcane. If
they close the factory, we'll be doomed.
Don't talk rubbish.
They won't close the factory.
Why would I lie about such
a thing, brother?
Even I've planted sugarcane
like all of you.
Stop. Now that you've brought this to me,
I'll look into the matter.
- Go.
- Alright, sir.
- We'll take your leave, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
What do you think, Ramachandrayya?
I don't know. We'll have to see.
If they do close the factory,
the whole village will suffer.
Do one thing.
Ask the Minister. He will know better.
What is this, Diwakar? Why are you so late?
What were you doing there this long?
Have you started already, without me?
Started? Gappi has finished three pots already.
Good going, Gappi.
Here, pour some.
Diwakar, your father is coming...
I don't like such petty jokes.
Why are you scared of your father?
What will he do? He will give you a long lecture. That's it, right?
That's enough to kill a person.
- By the way, are you staying back tomorrow as well?
- I'm leaving early in the morning.
Tomorrow if I don't report to the office,
my boss will kill me.
Dude, please take me along with you.
Look for a job for me in the city,
I'll go mad staying in this village.
You've been saying this for the last 10 years.
Come, I'll take you and get a job for you, will you?
I know you wouldn't, then why do you speak of it?
Moreover, will your father let you leave?
No, I'll come this time.
Okay, let's see.
I've heard you say this many times in the past.
- But this time, I'll come...
- Okay, let's see.
Are you happy now?
You got us scolded by the teacher. Mental!
Will you sleep peacefully tonight? Weirdo.
Guys, I got you caught for your own good!
Our good? We're going to fail,
how is that good?
Now we'll get hit at home too!
I got you two caught
because you were copying.
What did I do wrong?
Are you crazy?
Do you know what my father
will do if I fail?
But what will you achieve
by copying in the exam?
Copying is wrong. My grandfather says
it's as bad as cheating someone.
Really? You know what
my grandfather told me?
To hit you the same
number of times the teacher hit us.
Oh all right, your wish.
But don't hit too hard.
You think we were growing flowers in our
hands when he hit us? Show me your palm
- How many times did he hit you, Chenulu?
- Three times.
He hit me five times. Two extra
for showing you my paper.
So eight times in total.
Ah!
Ouch!
Does it hurt?
Will you dare get us caught again?
- Are we even?
- Yes, we are.
All right. Now go home and study.
If you copy again tomorrow, I won't be
able to stop myself from reporting you.
What! What is wrong with her?
You know, when Gandhiji was a student,
he did not copy even
when the teacher asked him to.
- Gandhi...
- Sister! Please stop.
You and your Gandhiji.
You know your Gandhiji roamed
with two young girls?
He also delayed our country's
independence, apparently.
We would have gotten it much earlier.
- Where are you going?
- You're both lying to me. I'm leaving.
We told you the truth. Ask anyone.
Fine. I'll go ask my Grandpa
if you guys are lying.
Sure. Ask him.
I've never understood what's the matter with her.
Crazy girl! She assumes to know all
but knows nothing.
How will she survive in this world?
What's wrong, Grandpa?
Why? Do I not look fine?
You're not happy. You look serious.
It's nothing, dear. The village is going
through a small crisis.
What happened?
Let it be, dear.
You're too young to understand.
Don't be sad. I don't like it.
You should always smile, like me.
Then paste your smile onto my face.
Look! It's stuck so well.
I am not able to stop smiling!
That's more like it.
Did you write your exam well?
I did.
What is it, dear?
Chenulu and Mallesh copied in the exam.
So, I reported them to the teacher.
The teacher hit them really hard…
and then they hit me.
What? They hit you?
Let me talk to them.
Let it be, Grandpa.
Why do you want to get involved?
We kids have our own issues. Let them be.
They're already angry with me.
They even said bad things about Gandhiji.
What did they say about Gandhiji?
That Gandhiji apparently used to roam
around with two girls.
They said he was not a good man.
Gandhiji was an old man, right?
To help him sit, make him stand and hold
there used to be two women
with him all the time.
That's all.
When you meet your friends tomorrow,
tell them this.
They also said our independence
got delayed because of Gandhiji.
Is that true?
Gandhiji went to jail.
He was beaten a lot.
He stayed hungry.
He suffered, but he never blamed anyone.
It doesn't take much time
to win using violence.
But if you want to win with love,
that takes a lot of time.
I'll go get Chenulu and Mallesh...
- would you tell them this too?
- Of course! I will tell them''
Come. Let us leave.
Oh! Pick that up, dear.
When you picked it up, you dusted it,
right?
Do the same with everything in life.
Dust off the bad. Keep the good.
All right! Here's your money.
Keep it. Buy some
sesame laddus for yourself.
When Suri comes...
you drag his leg and pull him down.
Then we'll all pounce on him.
Won't he get hurt, Mallesh?
I'll smack your face right now.
Of course, he'll get hurt.
If you don't want to play,
find a corner and sit quietly.
Okay, okay. I'll play.
Bro, she'll make us lose.
Kabaddi... Kabaddi...
- Kabaddi... Kabaddi...
- Sorry, sorry, sorry…
Sorry... Sorry... Sorry.
She is a mental case.
Are you mad?
Why are you saying sorry? Go sit.
- You're not playing, go sit.
- No, no. I want to play. Please, Chenulu.
It's useless to argue with her.
This time, send her in.
She'll get out quickly…
And then we can play in peace.
All right. Gandhi, this time you go!
- Me?
- Hmm.
Kabaddi… Kabaddi…
Ah! Ma…
Why is she screaming like this?
I don't know. I'm getting scared.
I'll go get someone.
Go.
Gandhi…
Gandhi!
Father-in-law, Gandhi got periods
Good to hear that, dear.
Gandhi?
Are you fine or still in pain?
My stomach hurts a lot, Grandpa.
There will be pain. You have to bear it.
Why are you talking like that, dear?
The child is in pain.
Give her some fenugreek seeds,
it'll help ease the pain.
All right.
Hold out your hand.
Don't touch anyone for a while.
- Why?
- When should we have her ceremony?
In 13 days. I'll invite my parents too.
They'll want to gift her a few things.
We'll set up a tent and arrange a
feast. Let's call everyone.
Why all the fuss, father?
What do you mean why, dear?
It's all for you.
You've become a big girl.
We must celebrate it.
So now, you'll invite everyone…
serve them lunch...
and announce that I've become a big girl?
I don't want all this.
I want to sit at home.
Grandpa, tell them not to!
Even when we want to do
something for you, you cry!
Always crying and complaining.
What kind of a girl are you?
What, child? What happened?
Grandpa, I don't want a ceremony.
Tell them. They won't listen to me.
Is a ceremony necessary, Yadamma?
The child is already in pain.
Every girl in the world gets her period.
What's there to celebrate about it?
How would it matter if we
don't have the ceremony?
We fall for the empty promises of men
Why do they always cheat us, Rajamma?
Have we women ever been given...
true freedom, sister?
We fall for the empty promises of men
Why do they always cheat us, Rajamma?
The preachings of a man are the same
as writings on water, sister
When they see Rani Rudramadevi
our men clap for her so loudly
But if we act brave with the men outside
we get thrashings from our man
"Look, our District Collector is a woman"
Our village men praise her
These same men get us married,
the moment we pass tenth grade
"We fall for their sweet praises
and become fools, Rajamma."
"Are we being punished for our naivety,
a perennial penance draped in our femininity?"
"We fall for their sweet praises
and become fools, Rajamma."
"Are we being punished for our naivety,
a perennial penance draped in our femininity?"
Hello, sir...
Hello...
Am I audible, sir?
Sir, it's me... Ellayya, the Sarpanch of Adluru.
Yes, Ellayya... What's the matter?
Sir, we are facing grave trouble.
The sugar factory owners are not buying our sugarcane.
They have sent back our vehicles.
We are heavily distressed.
Can you please help us out?
Ellayya, the government has already taken
the decision, we can't do anything now.
Now we can't change it for
your one village, can we?
How can you say that, sir?
The whole village is distressed.
Everyone has huge debts on them.
Don't talk like this, sir.
Please help us out.
Call me after a week.
Let me think about it.
We'll find some solution.
Sir, please don't say that.
You are our only hope.
Call me after a week.
Okay, sir.
Satish...
Sir...
Visit Adluru next week.
Sure, sir.
Gandhi! Are you coming or should we leave?
Yes! Wait a minute. I'm coming.
Gandhi, stop.
Why are you going with them?
Do you not have any shame?
You just became a big girl.
You can't mix with boys from now on.
- What will the villagers think?
- Ma, what are you saying?
I've been going to school with
them since forever.
What has changed now that I shouldn't?
I can't explain everything to you.
Just listen to me and don't go.
Boys! Leave! From today,
she won't walk to school with you.
Okay.
I'll ask your father to drop you.
Ma, don't you trust me?
- I do, dear. But the villagers...
- Forget the villagers.
You know they're my childhood
friends, right?
We have never done anything wrong.
So why punish us?
All right. Go!
I have complete trust in you. Go.
I don't know how she is going to live.
Guys wait.
What happened?
Why did your grandmother drive us out?
Are we not meeting each other henceforth?
What are you talking about?
We met now, didn't we?
Come, let's go. Come.
Hey, Gandhi. I heard you've come of age
and there was a function to celebrate that.
Why didn't you call me?
What nonsense are you talking about?
Don't worry, when you hit puberty,
I'll arrange a function for you too. Idiot!
It's okay. Leave.
Come.
You all know the sugar factory
is shutting down.
You all planted sugarcane, but the
factory is not in a position to buy it.
Certainly you will all lose your money.
Sir, do you have any solution?
I most certainly do.
After you've lost everything...
where will you get the money
to plant new crop?
That is why, to save and support
all of you...
our KTC company is planning to
set up a factory.
KTC... What factory is this, sir?
A chemical factory.
What? A chemical factory?
Yes.
A factory for your village!
Give us 150 acres.
Sell us your lands and we
will build a factory for you.
What will become of us?
I know exactly what you're all thinking.
If this factory comes,
imagine how your village will flourish!
We will give you jobs.
Tomorrow, you children will
also have jobs.
We'll build a hospital. We'll lay roads.
We'll even build houses for all of you.
We will help you through every difficulty.
This factory will be with you and
for you at all times.
If you build this factory,
won't our village be destroyed?
I want to uplift your village
and he's talking about damage.
I have come to help you.
In such times, what is more important?
Your lands or your lives?
Think carefully.
One more thing.
You have two weeks to come to a decision.
The minister told me you're all desperate
and in dire need of money.
So I came here.
Else, I would have gone to
another village.
Go home and think carefully.
He is offering five lakh rupees per acre.
Lands in this area don't even go for three
lakh rupees. Better for us to sell.
Yes, brother! Even I'm thinking of selling
and moving to the city.
we planted Sugarcane.
The factory is not buying
what do we do?
You get sugar cane juice right?
All of you take out sugar cane juice and
drink it.
We have been thinking all this time.
I have also been thinking the same way.
I will along with you.
Lakshmi, can you loan me two hundred
rupees? I'll pay you back next month.
I don't have money, sister. I haven't even
paid my daughter's school fees.
We are living a life of compromise.
We don't even have the money
to buy groceries.
- Suri!
- Greetings, sir.
- How's it going with you?
- Nothing to speak of, sir..
I am moving to the city next week.
I'll work there as a handyman.
Who will take care of your fields
if you go there and work as a handyman?
Uh, I don't know how to tell you this.
I'm planning to sell my fields, sir.
You want to sell your fields? What will
you do after selling your fields?
I had taken a loan for my
daughter's wedding.
Once I repay that, I'll feel much lighter.
I'll save the remaining money
and work in the city as a handyman.
I'll come back once
the factory is set up, sir.
Who are you selling your fields to?
The same gentleman from the city
who came the other day.
I plan on selling to him.
Are you out of your mind, Suri?
If you all care only about yourselves,
what will happen to the village?
Why are you scolding me
as if I'm the only one going, sir?
Villagers are planning to sell
their fields.
Also, everyone is in a bad situation.
You tell him. You're selling your land,
aren't you?
Yes sir.
The situation at home is very bad.
So? If conditions are bad, will you sell
the village itself?
Then, you give us money, sir.
Everyone's problems will be solved.
Everyone comes forward to advise.
But no one comes to help.
We are almost done.
There is still this 15-acre property near
the main road.
Who owns it? They didn't come.
An old man.
He is very stubborn.
He won't sell his land, sir.
He won't sell? How can he not?
If he doesn't sell his land, we won't be
able to lay the road.
Go and talk to him.
He's very stubborn, sir.
Even if I talk to him, he won't listen.
It's better if you talk to him.
Fine. I'll go talk to him.
Where does he stay?
There's a field back there.
There's a huge tree in the middle.
He'll be sitting underneath it.
Bring the car.
Sir, vehicles can't go there.
Then how will we get there?
Excuse me.
Are you Ramachandrayya?
Yes.
Please sit.
I knew you would create a nuisance.
I have not created any nuisance.
In fact, you came here with the wrong intention,
to destroy our village.
I'm just doing the right thing.
My father worked for the Britishers.
Later, inspired by Mahatma Gandhi,
he quit his job and became a freedom fighter.
Speaking English won't make us great, son.
What makes a man great are his ideals
and his dedication towards them.
Hey, why are you scaring him?
I'm talking to him, have some patience.
I'll come to the point.
It seems you don't wish to sell your land.
If you don't sell, how will we lay
our road?
So if I don't sell my land,
you have no other option?
Tell me how much you want.
I'll try and get you the best price.
What is your name, son?
Satish.
Satish?
if I sell you this land,
will you cut this tree?
Of course! If we are to build our road,
we have to take down the tree.
Have you ever heard of the
Thotaramudu story?
Yeah. Long ago.
Why bring it up now?
Just like Thotaramudu,
whose life was stuck in a parrot...
my life is stuck in this tree.
What? In this tree?
Okay. So what are you trying to say?
If you cut down this tree,
I will lose my life.
If I know I'm going to lose my life,
why would I sell my land to you?
Buy another land with a
similar tree in it.
Won't you find
such a tree elsewhere?
This is too much.
When Gandhiji died,
my father and I planted this tree in
his remembrance.
Sentiment. Very nice.
You must be around 30?
I am 32.
How many trees have you
planted in all your life?
My balcony is full of money plants.
Some 10-15 plants easily.
Will they provide enough oxygen
to you for your entire life?
I have planted lakhs of trees in
my lifetime.
You are alive because of trees
planted by someone else.
Actually, you have no right over the air
you are breathing.
Do you know that?
So?
So what right do you have to cut
this tree?
Forget an axe. I won't let you even
lay your finger on this tree.
I won't sell my land, son. You can leave.
Okay.
I'll leave. Let's talk peacefully later.
That won't be needed, son.
Leave. Take care.
Tough guy.
I won't let anything happen to you.
I'm here. I'll take care of you.
All right?
Well, brother? I hear you're not selling
your land?
My father won't budge.
Everyone in the village has sold
their land. Except you.
They're saying they won't start
construction unless you sell.
Everyone is speaking ill about you
and your family.
My father is stubborn.
He won't listen to me.
Then be firm with him.
Are you still a child?
If you don't need money, fine.
But, think about the others.
Everyone in the village is in debt.
Has Gandhi eaten?
Yes, she has.
Father, I need to speak with you.
Tell me.
Father...
Everyone in the village is angry
that we haven't sold our land.
Our land is near the road.
They'll give us a good rate!
If we want, we can ask for more.
How can you even think
such a thought, son?
Did you buy this land?
My father gave me this land.
I must protect it. Not sell it.
Father, we are not getting good yield.
Even if we do, we do not get a good price.
When they'll close the sugar factory,
we'll be out of options.
When it doesn't bring us earnings,
why do you want to keep the land?
I'll move to the city and work.
Stop blabbering.
Says he wants to sell the land.
It's wrong, son.
To sell the land that feeds us...
is like making your mother a prostitute.
My mother lived a miserable life
because of you.
She lived an unhappy life.
Do you want my family
to go through the same pain?
Do you not want any of us to be happy?
There is no happiness in city life, son.
Here, we live like kings.
When you can't
protect the land under your feet,
do you think you will fly in the city?
Whether you sell or not,
I'm leaving this village.
I'll take a loan and
leave, if I have to.
Also, that land is my grandfather's
property. It's my inheritance, not yours.
Why are you speaking to your father like
that? Give him some respect.
I am also 40 years old. It will be
better for him to give respect to me.
No matter what you say.
As long as I live,
I am not selling the land.
Then please die!
I'll sell the land.
At least we will be happy.
Have you gone mad?
How can you talk to your father like that?
Father-in-law, please don't get up.
It's okay, dear.
I'm leaving.
"At the stroke of the midnight hour
when the world sleeps."
"India will awake to
light and freedom!"
What is Nehru saying, sir?
Tell us, sir.
Nehru says we have got our independence!
What does that mean, father?
Today, good triumphed over evil, son.
We are free now.
"Eashwar, Allah, all your divine names..."
"Grant us wisdom and harmony, O Lord."
"Grant us companionship, O Lord."
No, no. Not Sangati. It's 'Sanmati'.
- Sanmati.
- San-mati.
Sanmati means,''Give us all good thoughts
O God''
Who is praying to whom, father?
Our Gandhiji, son.
Jesus, Allah and Ram. He's praying that
they bless us with purity of thought!
Why is Gandhiji praying for that, father?
If everyone had pure thoughts,
even the biggest battles would be
resolved peacefully!
If someone were to hit you on your face,
we must turn our other cheek to them.
If we turn the other cheek,
they'll hit us again, father.
Yes, they will.
But soon they'll get tired of hitting you.
Tired, they'll leave, and let you be.
Our Gandhiji brought us Independence
the same way, son.
- Really?
- Yes!
Walk carefully, son. You'll fall.
Nothing will happen. You're there for me.
Mahatma Gandhi is dead.
The funeral procession across the land,
now plunged into grief.
Why are you crying, son?
Gandhiji passed away, father.
They just announced it on the radio.
Why did he leave before
I could meet him?
It's okay if you couldn't meet Bapu.
Because Bapu is always
looking at you from above.
Wipe your tears, son.
Wipe your tears.
Now that Gandhiji has passed,
everyone will forget him. Won't they?
How can they forget him, son?
They call him 'Father of the Nation'.
Will you ever forget me, your father?
How could I forget you, father?
Exactly, he's the father of our
entire nation.
How could we forget him?
Let's do something to honor our Bapu.
Come with me.
If I plant this tree, will I always
remember Bapu, father?
If you plant this tree, it'll grow big...
It will provide pleasant shade,
a cool breeze,
and look after everyone.
You're planting this tree with such
pure intentions,
Bapu will be proud of you.
For caring about the
people of this village.
Bapu will always be with you.
Sow the seed, son.
All right.
Take great care of this sapling.
Yes, father.
As long as this grows,
Bapu will always be with you.
- Understood, son?
- Yes, father.
What's it, Grandpa?
You're still here?
Come, let's go home.
Come here, child. Sit with me.
What happened, Grandpa?
Are you all right? Have you eaten?
My sweet Gandhi.
Always thinking about others' happiness.
Stay blessed, child.
You stay blessed too, my sweet Grandpa!
Come. Let's go home.
Dear,
I taught you 'Raghupati
Raghava Raja Ram', did I not?
Do you still remember the song?
Yes, I do.
I even got the first prize
when I sang it in fifth grade.
Will you sing the song for me, once?
Now?
Yes. Now.
Scion of the clan of Raghu
Lord Raam
Uplifter of the fallen
Sita's helpmeet Raam
Eashwar, Allah
All your divine names
Grant us wisdom and Harmony
O Lord
Do you remember the meaning of the song?
Ram, Eashwar, and Allah.
They are all one.
We pray to God
to bless everyone with pure thoughts.
Yes, we should pray to God.
You have to promise me something, child.
Will you?
Tell me. What do you want me
to promise you?
Will you protect my tree at all costs?
Okay. I'll protect it.
Promise?
I promise you, Grandpa.
Nothing will ever happen to your tree.
Now let's go home. I'm hungry.
I'm very tired, child.
You go on, I'll be along.
Come fast. I won't eat if
you're not there.
You eat, dear. I'll come in a while.
The old man doesn't want to sell.
Why are you tormenting him?
Let him have it as long as he's around.
Sell the land after.
We have no money! We need to save up for
our daughter's wedding.
If I sit around and do nothing,
where will we get money from?
I'm still healthy enough to work and
earn some money. Is that wrong?
What, dear? What are you doing here?
Where's Grandpa?
Grandpa said he'll come soon.
Okay. Come inside and eat.
No. I won't eat until Grandpa comes.
He's never this late.
I'll go get him.
No, you won't.
I'll send your father. Wait.
What happened?
Your father hasn’t come back.
Will you go check where he is?
He'll come back home, don't worry.
It's not that. He's never this late!
Go check on him, once.
Listen to me, please.
- Gandhi wants to go alone.
- Alright. I'll go.
Let's go.
Come home quickly.
Look! Grandpa's still sitting there.
Grandpa!
Grandpa! Come, let's go home.
Grandpa.
Rama...
The rays of the sun touch me everyday...
But they lack the warmth of your hands.
We so many conversations left unfinished.
Come, sleep in my shade.
Come ,Sit here.
Complain about your son.
Do come...
Remind your father
Talk about your wife.
Tell me about your granddaughter.
If you are happy! You held me and laughed.
Vented your pain to me.
Where have you gone, Rama?
Won't you share your
joys and sorrows with me?
My branches ask after you.
My roots search for you.
My bark feels heavier than ever.
I wish I had eyes.
I would have cast off
this burden to be with you.
Alas…
Why did you have to weep for me?
If I'm gone, there are a hundred trees
like me.
You left the moment God called to you.
Do you love God more than me?
Without you, these branches and
leaves feel useless.
I don't want this life anymore.
You made this decision to leave.
Could you not have
taken me with you, Rama?
Why, Rama?
Why did you leave me and go?
Rama...
Diwakar, how are you doing?
I don't know.
I still haven't processed his death.
Your father had a pure heart.
He always wished everyone well.
The Gods will look after him
wherever he is.
Are you Ramachandrayya's son?
Yes.
Can we step aside,
I want to talk to you.
Tell me.
Please let's step aside.
You hold a degree. Degree in what?
I am a B.Com graduate, sir.
B.Com... B.Com graduate but involved in farming.
What can I do, sir?
Is your job anywhere related to your education?
My father wants me to...
How much do you earn every month?
Nothing much, sir.
Then how would you take care of your wife?
Are you understanding what I'm saying?
Listen, I can understand your situation.
I know I shouldn't bring it up
during this time.
This is not your issue alone.
- It affects the whole village.
- First tell me what is this about, sir?
Listen.
In six months, we are going
to start construction.
I have to complete all the
acquisitions in this month.
Everyone in the village peacefully
completed their registration.
Only yours remains.
I am still mourning my father's death.
Listen. I know you have a
one lakh rupee loan.
Don't you?
Yeah, I do. So what?
How are you going to repay it?
I don't want your money, sir.
- I don't want your money.
- Keep this one lakh.
Repay your loan.
You'll feel lighter.
Now that your father has
passed, consider me your brother.
Diwakar.
I gave everyone 5 lakh rupees per acre.
I'll give you 6 lakh rupees.
In fact, I'll give you
7 lakh rupees.
Because you're like a brother to me.
Okay.
Even if you don't sell your
land, this one lakh is yours.
Listen.
I'll wait for you at
the Village Head's office at 4' o clock.
I'll see you there.
But sir...
Enough, child.
How much longer will you cry?
I don't know, Ma.
I tried to forget Grandpa.
But I'm unable to.
I know, dear.
Seeing you cry like this,
I feel bad too.
Yadamma!
Look! Your dad's here.
Can you fetch me some water?
Look at her.
She's been crying for so long.
Just talk to her.
Look what I got you. Take it.
I don't want anything.
Eat it, Child!
Take this.
I'm sad too that Grandpa is no more.
After all, he is my father.
But there is nothing we can do.
Life does not stop for anyone.
Grandpa adored you.
He showered you with so much love.
You should remember
all that love and be happy.
Okay?
Here.
I got them for you.
It's been many days
since you had sesame laddus.
Eat, dear. Eat.
I see! So...
if your father asks you, you'll eat.
But if your mother asks you, you won't?
Is that it?
Obviously!
My daughter will always be on my side.
She'll only listen to me.
Nothing like that.
I'll listen to both of you!
I know, dear.
I'm kidding.
I was just teasing your mother.
Also, we'll be moving
to the city in three months!
I'll admit her in a big private school.
You'll be happy.
You'll make lots of friends there.
Okay?
How will we move to the city?
Which city? How will we get there?
We don't have the money to move.
I have sold our land, Yadamma.
Dad...
Those who bought the land...
will they do anything to Grandpa's tree?
Once you've sold them the land,
they can do whatever they want.
They can cut the tree or count the store
there. It's their wish.
Once we sell our land,
we don't have any say.
Then don't sell.
Go on, dear. Go sleep.
Don't think about all this.
Also, you are a girl.
You should do what we say.
Live the way we tell you to.
Then only it will do good to you.
Father, I am not going to leave
the village.
I promised Grandpa that I would
protect his tree at all costs.
Tree... Tree... that goddamn tree!
Your Grandpa hung around that tree
his whole life.
Seems he passed his
madness on to you.
Everyone in the village used to
laugh at him.
Called him mad for always talking
with that tree.
So what, father?
Grandpa loved that tree.
What is wrong about that?
I swore to Grandpa.
He trusted me to protect that tree.
I have already sold the land.
Understand?
Anyway, you're just a child.
Why should I listen to you?
From now on, I will decide everything.
My wish! I will do whatever I please.
Do you understand?
Go. Go inside!
Gandhi!
Where were you the entire evening?
Your father was very angry at you,
he just went to sleep.
It's been late, why didn't you go to sleep?
How can I sleep without you?
Ma, why did Dad have to sell the land?
Psst...
Are you still thinking about that?
Let it go.
We should do whatever dad says.
Okay?
But I gave Grandpa my word.
Poor Grandpa! I'm sure he feels bad.
He put his trust in me.
What can you do now, Gandhi?
Tell me, what can you do.
I'll do something
so that we earn back our money.
That way, we can buy back our land.
It's not that easy, dear.
How do you plan to make money?
Hm?
I don't know.
No clue.
But I'll definitely save that tree.
Or else Grandpa will feel bad.
Look at you.
You think about those alive.
You think about those who're gone.
If you keep thinking about everyone else,
how will you survive in this world?
It's late. Come and have dinner.
Gandhi…
Gandhi!
Tsk. Eat and sleep, child.
How will you survive, dear?
You don't get angry, don't hurt others,
don't know how to lie to others...
It's not possible to live
an idealistic life like your grandfather.
This world is too cruel towards good people.
Sin theta...
by Cos theta...
is equal to...
Tan theta.
Miss Attentive!
You don't want to take notes? You think
you can remember everything?
No, sir.
I can't see the board clearly.
Silence!
Your eyesight's grown weak.
You may have to
start wearing spectacles.
Go get checked by the eye doctor in town.
Ask your father to take you.
My father won't take me.
He's angry with me.
Shall I take you?
Would you?
I have around...
seven rupees.
Sine…
Grandpa told me you were his best friend.
I don't know why he asked me to
protect you.
No one will listen to me.
Have you got any ideas?
The Truth Crusade!
Can we go home now?
Let's wait a little longer, Mallesh.
You're always in a hurry to go
home, saying
your mom will scold you or your dad
will hit you.
How come today
you suddenly want to stay longer?
Is everything okay at home?
Things are fine.
Can you guys give me some ideas?
I want to save the tree.
We don't have any. Ask your Gandhiji.
Gandhiji would have…
advised us to do a Salt Satyagraha!
But we don't have a sea in our village.
That's okay. If not a Salt Satyagraha
you can do a Sugar Satyagraha.
The whole village is filled
with sugarcane.
Sugar Satyagraha?
Yeah, Gandhi.
Take all the sugarcane in the village...
and make sugar.
We can sell the sugar.
We'll make a lot of money!
Done! Let's find out how to make sugar.
Urgent.
Bro, what's wrong with her?
She gets weirder everyday.
I swear, Mallesh.
I went to the temple yesterday.
I promised Goddess Yellama I'll buy her a
nice saree, if she cures Gandhi.
Ma, do you know how to make sugar?
Sugar?
There's lots of it at home.
Do you want to eat some?
That's not what I'm asking.
Can we make sugar at home?
How can one make sugar
at home, child?
They make it in factories.
How do they process sugar?
They make sugar with the help of some machines.
Leave it all..
If you want sugar, I'll give you some.
Hey! Do you know how to make sugar?
Brother...
Do you know how to make sugar?
Sugar?
They make it in the factory.
How do they make it in the factory?
They put sugarcane in a machine...
it comes out as sugar.
Can we make sugar without machines?
I don't know, dear.
Okay.
I'll leave now.
P...
T...
O-C.
PTOC.
Sir, do you know how to make sugar?
Sugar?
You take some sugarcane.
Throw it in a big boiler and boil it.
Afterwards, mix molasses
in the boiler.
As a result, a layer will be formed...
Is Chenulu awake, Aunty?
What are you doing here so late?
Pack some sugarcane and
come to the fort tomorrow.
Tomorrow is a Sunday, Gandhi.
You woke me up
to tell me to bring sugarcane juice?
We are going to make Sugar tomorrow!
Weren't you the one who gave me the
Sugar Satyagraha idea?
Fine. I'll do it. Now go home.
Idiot wants sugarcane juice
in the middle of the night.
Hey Gandhi, are you making Sugar?
If you don't make sugar, you will die in
our hands
I gave you the idea. If this works,
you have to give me credit.
Understood?
What is happening?
It needs to get thicker.
So make it thicker.
I shouldn't have to make it.
It should get thicker by itself.
Why does it look like this?
They told me if I make it like this,
it'll become sugar.
That lunatic told you
and you followed it blindly.
Please don't tell anyone
this was my idea.
Do you understand?
I'll lose my reputation in the village.
Why are you crying, Gandhi?
I thought that if we manage to make sugar,
we could solve all
the problems in the village.
I knew something like this would happen.
Don't cry, Gandhi.
Look, at least you tried.
- Where you going?
- She is going to make sugar, as if !
Gandhi...
Your mother asked for lentils...
Why are you crying?
What happened, dear?
Come, sit with me.
What's that in your hand?
Do you want laddus?
- No.
- Let me get some!
No brother, I really don't want it.
What happened, dear?
Why are you so sad?
I thought I could make sugar.
But I made a mess instead.
Really? Show me.
Dear, you set out to make sugar,
but you've made jaggery instead!
What?
Show me your palm.
Put it in your mouth
Oh yes, brother, this is jaggery!
One must never cry on a Sunday.
Go. Go play with your friends.
Okay Brother, Thank you.
Bye.
Child your bag!
Brother!
Can I get 1 kilo of jaggery?
Jaggery... I'm out of jaggery.
I'll get some tomorrow.
What? My daughter wants to make sweet
rice-pudding to offer at the temple.
I don't have any. Come tomorrow.
Fine.
Sister! Sister!
Come back, come back.
Gandhi made this jaggery.
What? Gandhi makes jaggery?
Yes. It tastes good too.
Weighs around 1 kg.
Should be enough, right?
- Yes.
- Here, take it.
Sister! This tastes so good.
How did you make it?
It tastes divine.
Isn't it?
My daughter makes
the same rice-pudding every year.
Must be because of the jaggery
from the shopkeeper.
Is that so?
- Our Gandhi made the jaggery!
- Gandhi knows how to make Jaggery?
- Yes.
- Even I want some.
Ask our shopkeeper.
Alright.
Brother...
do you have Gandhi's jaggery?
Gandhi jaggery?
What's that?
A new brand in town?
Samakka bought some the other day.
From your shop.
Oh! You mean the Jaggery
that Gandhi made?
That's over.
I'll give you something else.
No, we want only that. Get it for us.
Yes, I'll get it.
- It's compulsory.
- Okay, I'll get it.
What are you thinking now?
I beg you. Don't get any new ideas.
Aye...
Bro.
I think she'll make chilli powder,
now that the sugar idea flopped.
Guys, did I tell you?
The sugar I made the other day was
jaggery, the shopkeeper told me.
It's is not true. That can't be jaggery.
I swear. I ate it too.
Nah! If you'd eaten it, you'd be dead.
I swear, I'm not lying.
I left the bag with the shopkeeper.
You can taste it.
Brother.
I'm actually looking for you.
I left the bag of jaggery with you.
Do you have it?
That's over.
Can you make me another 10 kilos, child?
10 kilos?
The other day Samakka made sweet
rice-pudding with your jaggery.
Everyone in the village ate it and praised
your jaggery. They all want to buy it.
Can you make me some? I'll pay you.
You'll pay for that jaggery?
I'll pay. I need it urgently.
Many people are asking for it.
- Well? Can you make it?
- Yes.
- You will, right?
Come, let's go.
Brother,
swear on your wife and tell me.
Was that really Jaggery?
Aye... you go away.
Brother, can you give me some
sugarcane juice?
What's going on, child?
What are you up to?
I told you
I'm making 10 kilos of jaggery.
10 kilos of jaggery?
Mmm. You made all this jaggery?
Yes, ma.
With our sugarcane?
Mmm. It tastes so good, Gandhi!
How did you manage it?
I don't know. It must be
our village's sugarcane.
Grandpa used to say
there is nothing sweeter than
our village's sugarcane.
Just like us.
Is that so? I don't think so.
You made it, right?
That's why it's so sweet.
Show me your hand.
Didn't I tell you?
It's because of your hand.
Your hand tastes so sweet!
- How is it so sweet?
What will you do,
selling all this Jaggery?
I'll save up the money,
give it to the factory and
ask them to return all our lands.
I'll tell them we don't need
their factory.
I'll also tell them
not to cut Grandpa's tree.
My sweet child!
Oh Gandhi! Come here.
Tell me, sister.
I made sweet rice-pudding with your
jaggery. It tasted so good!
The shopkeeper told me. Thank you.
Do you have more?
I want to buy some.
I just gave the shopkeeper 10 kilos.
- You can buy some there.
- Alright.
Gandhi, how does one make Jaggery?
First, you take some sugarcane juice...
I don't know how to explain it, sister.
I'll make some and show you.
Show me.
I have a lot of sugarcane with me.
I'll also make and sell.
I'll get to make some money too.
Why do you want money, sister?
I'll give it to my husband. He'll buy back
our land. We sold our lands right?
Then all of you come here on Sunday.
Bring everyone.
I'll teach everyone.
Okay? Don't forget!
Such an innocent child. Don't know
how she'll survive in this world.
Diwakar, why don't you give
me a hundred rupees?
I don't have any money.
Why are you lying to me, Diwakar?
I heard your daughter is in
the jaggery business.
Gandhi?
Yeah, Diwakar.
No way. She's not that smart.
Also, why would I take
my daughter's money?
My wife is making sweets
with her jaggery today.
I swear, Diwakar.
My father spoiled her too much.
That is why she is crossing her limits.
Diwakar.
Listen to me. Get her married.
If she's already so independent,
she won't listen to you.
What do you mean, married?
She's still a small girl.
So? She's attained puberty, hasn't she?
You can get her married.
I heard you're making jaggery
and selling it to the shop.
Yes!
See, I made some money too!
I sent you to school to study.
Not to start selling jaggery.
Huh?
Did I ask you to do it?
Am I a joke now in this house?
Please calm down. She's a small
girl. She didn't think so much.
I'll talk her out of it.
Your Grandfather
pampered you too much.
That's why you're spoilt. Only way to set
you straight is to get you married.
Huh? What do you mean, marriage?
Have you gone mad?
You go inside.
- She's a small chi...
- She's no more a small child.
She's hit puberty.
Yadagiri saw her
at the temple the other day.
- I told them she's ready.
- They're coming tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Father.
They're coming tomorrow.
If they like you, I'm getting you married.
No more studies.
What? Why do you want
to get her married now?
Please reconsider your decision.
She is doing as she pleases. Unless we get
her married, she won't come to her senses.
I didn't do all this...
to make you angry, Father.
I just wanted to help you.
You do without getting angry
From now on, don't do anything.
I can take care of things at home.
Gandhi, are you awake?
The boy's parents are on their
way to see you.
Where are you off to?
I have something urgent to do.
I'll be right back.
If you're not here by the time they come,
your father will kill me.
- I'll be back by the time they come.
- Be quick!
Brother!
Tell me, Gandhi.
Where's your daughter, brother?
You've offered us the same drink
three times since we came.
She'll be back. She's gone to the
shop nearby.
I only sent her.
Where did she go?
Is she coming or not?
Are you sure you want this?
I am serious, brother!
Once I remove it, you can't stick it back.
I know. Remove it.
Have you pledged your hair to God?
Nothing like that. Why?
Let me remove a little? It'll look good.
No, brother. Go ahead.
Shave my head.
It's just hair. It'll grow back.
I warned you. Now it's your wish.
"Like the goddess Lakshmi,
your face is so bright,"
"Your mother says a beauty
spot on it looks very pretty."
" Your eyes are so wide like a lake"
"The black kohl makes it so attractive."
"Your thick curly hair is the
secret behind your beauty."
"The earrings for your ears are so lovely"
"But, Oh moon, what is real beauty?
Tell me, Oh moon."
"The bangles, the clothes, the powder, the perfume"
"The flowers in your hair,
everything will fade away in a day…"
"The courage in your heart is the true beauty"
"The sparkle in your eyes is timeless beauty"
"To wear bravery on your sleeve is the finest beauty"
"The path you believe in is so beautiful for you"
"The wish you like is so beautiful for you"
"Beauty is when you stand on your own feet"
"Beauty is when you help others with your spirit"
"Oh, my dear moon,
Oh, my dear moon"
Is this your girl?
Yes, sister.
Why didn't you tell us your girl
was bald?
I shaved my hair just now.
My parents too just got to know.
If the girl is bald,
she won't look good in the wedding.
We'll leave now.
You have shamed me in front of everyone.
Stop, now.
You scared her with all this.
That's why she shaved her head.
I'll find someone who'll agree to marry
you, even if you are bald.
Why did you do this?
Once upon a time, a bird left its nest
and flew away
One by one, all the other
birds also flew the same way
Once, a drop of rain fell on the ground
All the clouds followed the raindrop
and poured themselves down
With a fistful of salt and fire
in his heart,
Gandhi performed
the Dandi March one day
With a piece of sugarcane and with
sweetness in her heart
this Gandhi started
her stubborn march that day
With a lean body and a heart of iron,
Gandhi walked ahead alone
Determined to find the solution, this girl
walked ahead with resolution
She hugged the branch and called the
tree her own
When crisis arose in the village,
she decided to fight
Wilfully she walked the path of thorns
And then, the whole village decided
to join
A fighter!
This girl is a fighter!
Once upon a time, a bird left its nest
and flew away
One by one, all the other
birds also flew the same way
Once, a drop of rain fell on the ground
All the clouds followed the raindrop
and poured themselves down
A fighter!
This girl is a fighter!
Mallesh and Chenulu, I have an idea.
Now that we are making more money.
we can ask all the villagers to buy
back their land.
Land... Land...
always talking about Land.
Sister...
Brother.
How did this happen, sister?
What can I tell you, brother?
The whole village is suffering like me.
Six people have died so far.
I begged him.. Not to sell our lands to
the factory people.
But he sold them. It's been two years.
We have no food to feed ourselves.
We've exhausted all the money
we earned by selling our land.
And now, he's left us. Could he not have
taken me and the kids with him?
What is the point of me living?
How could Suresh die so suddenly?
Now what are his wife and kids
going to do?
Even the neighbouring villages sold their
land and got duped by the factory people.
What will become of us?
I'm really scared now.
Ramachandrayya was right.
He told us many times not to sell
our lands. That we'd be ruined.
None of us listened to him.
Hey Diwakar, how are you?
Your girl has turned out really sharp.
It seems she earned 1200 rupees
in a month!
You did a fine job raising her.
She's gone to sleep.
She's been running around a lot.
The whole village is running behind her.
It's getting on my nerves.
Did she do something again?
Are you angry?
If you are, please talk to her in
the morning.
I feel bad for her.
She's very tired.
Don't wake her up.
What happened?
All these years,
I've never seen you cry even once.
What happened, dear?
Why are you falling at her feet?
Our daughter is truly great.
My mother named me Diwakar, after her
father's name.
But my father,
he knew the whole village
would talk about her.
That's why he wisely named
her 'Gandhi'.
I have caused her great pain.
My sweet child.
Did you realise? She never once
raised her voice against me.
She never once got angry with me.
From whom did she learn to be so good?
Most certainly not from us.
I made a huge mistake, Yadamma.
Never once did I try to understand her.
I should have at least tried.
She would have achieved
so much more.
My daughter will forgive me, won't she?
Sorry, I'm not getting my daughter married so soon.
Have gone mad, Diwakar?
You called us to talk about the alliance, didn't you?
Sorry, brother.
My daughter has to achieve a lot in her life.
Let her live her life as she wishes.
Great job! You have insulted us well!
When the neighbouring village people
started dying,
Our people became wise.
They realized their mistake.
They went to the Village Head.
Didn't you all sign? You've already sold
your land. The damage is done.
Satish sir is coming to town in two days.
There's nothing we can do now. Go home.
All of you. Leave.
Someone called Satish is coming
to our village in a couple of days.
What will happen if Satish comes here?
You, fool... If he builds a factory here,
we all will be driven out of this village.
The village will be vacant,
we will be separated forever.
Our parents have sold their lands,
now we have to make them re-purchase it.
I don't understand anything.
Do you like our village?
A lot.
Why?
We are born here and we live here.
Our village is a beautiful place.
Isn't it? But if they build their factory,
all the fields will be gone and so will we.
We should all do the "Simon, go back!"
Simon, what?
A white man named Simon
came to our country to loot us.
But Gandhiji assembled everyone,
stood outside the train station
and shouted "Simon, go back!"
till he left.
What is it?
"Simon, go back!"
The same way, we should
shout, "Satish, go back!"
Do you all understand?
- Satish, go back!
- Yes! Just like that.
Now, everyone shout.
- Satish!
- Go back!
What is this nonsense?
Vehicles will hit you.
Why these guys are not moving?
Hey kids. Move aside.
Blow the horn more
I'm running out of time,
what game are you kids playing at?
What do you want?
Satish!
Go Back!
- Satish!
- Go Back!
Satish!
Go Back!
- Satish
- Go Back!
Have they gone crazy?
Ask them to move.
No idea, sir, they won't listen to us.
They won't tell us what happened either.
They are yelling something in English.
We don't understand them.
They want me to go back!
- Is that so?
- Tell them to move!
Kids, get up!
Get up. I am talking to you, boy.
Sir, these kids simply
won't listen to us.
Let them be. Why don't you
come back tomorrow.
What! Here comes your Village Head.
I will talk to him.
What happened, sir?
They're not allowing me to enter. They're
shouting, "Satish, Go Back!".
Kids, what is this fuss? Please get up.
- Get all of them up.
- All of you, get up.
All of you, get up!
They're not moving, sir.
Shall I hit them?
Don't be an idiot.
Go get their parents.
Hey Kids. Don't you want to listen to us?
How much longer do I have to wait?
I've become a bloody joke to them.
Let's leave
- What's up with the kids?
- Why are they sitting here?
What is wrong with them?
Did anyone do anything to them?
What do you want?
Give back our lands.
We will sell jaggery and pay you back.
How is that possible?
Or else we won't get up.
Village Head, if they don't get up,
I will have to call the Minister.
You know what the
consequences will be.
Just wait a while, sir.
Go move your kids.
- Move them immediately
- Drag them away if you have to.
Over actions.
This is what happens when you
mess with me.
Please spare my Grandfather's tree.
I promised my Grandfather
I would protect it.
Oh, I see!
So, the tree is the issue. That means if I
take it down, you'll learn your lesson.
Get lost.
Make way for me.
- My god! -He is planning to cut down
Ramachandrayya's tree.
You have to let it go.
Please tell them not to, father.
Please tell them not to cut down the tree.
You tried your best to stop this.
Let it go.
You have to let it go.
What are you looking at?
Start chopping.
Brother!
Sir, this tree is bleeding.
What? Blood?
Blood?
Show me.
They say the tree is bleeding.
- The tree is bleeding...
- The tree is bleeding…
I have never seen such a thing
in my life.
What is this, priest?
Don't panic, all of you.
I will be right back.
What is this, sir?
I my whole life,
I've never seen a tree bleed!
Why do you think it's bleeding?
How would I know? Only God knows why!
- God?
- Yes, it's probably God's miracle.
This is God's doing, the
Village Head just said so.
Look madam, that is not what he meant.
He only said, God knows why it's bleeding.
Red bus candidates.
Keep quiet. All of you,
stop making wild guesses.
I don't know if this is God's doing.
Then what's there in the tree?
Why is blood oozing out of the tree?
I think Ramachanraayya's spirit
is in the tree.
What, is there a ghost in it?
Our Ramachandrayya was a good man.
How can he be a ghost?
Will y'all please shut up?
Always making a drama out of everything.
Why have you guys stopped?
Dad, what is there in the tree?
I have no idea, dear.
I can't understand anything either.
Please step aside.
Turmeric can stop the bleeding.
Each of you, come forward and apply
turmeric to the tree.
Oh sister, where are you going?
This is not a good omen.
A tree bleeding is not a minor thing.
This does not mean well for you or for
the village.
Okay, thank you!
Now all of you can leave.
I will take care of my tree.
Why are you staring at me like that?
Please sir, why are you
talking like that?
Don't be stubborn and cut it down.
- I am requesting you. sir. Please leave.
- Yes, sir.
It is against God's will for you
to construct a factory.
We are begging you, sir. Give back our
lands.
We don't want a factory.
- We will give back your money.
- Yes sir. We will, sir. Please, sir.
- Yes sir.
- Please sir.
Is this some kind of a joke?
Hey you, go chop that tree.
I'm scared, sir.
What are you scared of?
Give me the axe.
Sir... Sir... I beg you. Sir
Who knows what is there in that tree?
Could be god, ghost, or Ramachandarayya.
Spare the tree, sir.
Hey, who are you to talk to me
like this?
- He pushed Sir. Don't spare him.
- Get him!
How dare he push our Village
Head. Get him!
Beat him up! This is all because of him.
He came to ruin us.
We won't let you go, sir.
Please don't hit him.
Gandhi, what are you doing?
Step aside.
I won't step aside.
It's all my fault, so hit me.
You don't know anything, Gandhi.
He cheated all of us.
He grabbed our lands.
Step aside. We will teach him a lesson.
I'm not moving from here.
Move aside.
Scion of the Raghu clan
Lord Raam
Uplifter of the fallen
Sita's helpmeet Raam
Eashwar Allah
All your divine names
Grant us wisdom and Harmony
O Lord
Gandhi's words
were her blessing
They became the light
that showed her the path
Let the violence end
Let love be the answer
Let truth win
Today
Let kindness be
our religion
Let us do a Satyagraha to
fight for what is right
Scion of the clan of Raghu, Lord Raam
Uplifter of the fallen,
Sita's helpmeet Raam
Eashwar, Allah, all your divine names
Grant us wisdom and harmony, O Lord
Scion of the clan of Raghu, Lord Raam
Uplifter of the fallen,
Sita's helpmeet Raam
Ah! Ouch!
It still hurts a little.
But I am very happy today.
Everyone was surprised to see a
tree bleed.
Who would believe it?
But I was surprised to see our Gandhi.
Our little Gandhi who learnt to walk
and talk just yesterday,
saved the entire village. My god.
If Ramachandrayya were alive,
he would have been so proud!
From where did she get this strength?
Some people are like that.
They are not limited.
They can achieve anything.
Everyone wants to join hands with them.
The whole world.
Even Nature supports them.
When Lord Ram laid rocks in the ocean,
they floated.
When Lord Krishna tried
to lift the mountain,
the mountain sat on
his little finger.
If you were to ask why,
the answer is in their intentions.
They intended the good of everyone.
Our Gandhi's intention was good,
and so our village won.
Good won in our village.
That's it! That's our story.
If you ever come around here,
come to our village.
I can't move from here anyway.
You see the temple there,
if you turn right from
there and come into the fields.
I'll be right here.
See you!